THIS PROGRAM CONTAINS
AI-GENERATED CONTENT
[♪ suspenseful music playing]
GRAND PRINCE HWIRYEONG
The national coffers are empty,
but the powerful grow richer by the day.
Taxes wrung
from the people's blood and sweat
are being pocketed along the way.
Lord Yun.
Are you not in a position
to advise His Majesty to do what is right?
I have heard that while the people starve,
the court is falsifying records
of abundant harvests.
For the sake of the people,
as your humble servant,
I shall dare to write a petition.
[♪ theme song playing]
MURDER CLUB: LIAR'S TABLE
I'll be strategic and open one more.
- You had two?
- Yes.
PLENTY OF BONUS CARDS
- [Igyeong] He'll open them all.
- At least he's handsome.
- I like him.
- [laughing]
Gosh, ma'am.
What's that?
- Oh, my.
- [Suyeon] "Yun Igyeong…"
- [contestants] "Yun Igyeong."
- "Eliminate."
- "Office."
[gasps] They heard
you were being eliminated.
Dad, someone tried to eliminate you.
Gosh, I nearly died.
- Kill Yun Igyeong and gain office.
- They meant to kill me instead?
- I think so.
- That says--
Gosh, this is really fun.
Number nine, please.
PICTURE OF THE CRIME SCENE
- [Bokgil] What's that?
- A picture?
It's the scene of the crime.
[Igyeong] It's a pair of shoes!
Look closely at the footprints.
- Where are they headed?
- Shoes?
They came out from here
and walked that way.
This is the kitchen.
That's where the trail of blood started.
[Suyeon] Someone was in the kitchen.
THE KITCHEN IS THE SOURCE
- Where were you at that time?
- [Musoe] Lady Yun.
I know that you planned
to run away in the middle of the night.
Did you not meet Bokgil?
I told you I was just in my room.
- The whole night?
- Yes.
- But--
- I never left the house.
You only planned to run away?
I planned to run away,
but I never actually left the house.
If you were in your room,
where was Bokgil?
I was just out for a walk.
I like exercising at night.
- I'm serious.
- [Suyeon] You took a walk?
- That's so suspicious.
- I just…
[Bokgil] It was a nice, moonlit night
so I did some light exercise.
- Exercise under the moonlight?
- Yes.
BOKGIL, A MAN OF MYSTERY
One thing's for sure.
Bokgil is no ordinary slave.
- No, he isn't.
- [Suyeon] I think someone higher up
hired him to infiltrate as a slave--
- [laughs] Oh, please.
- He's an undercover slave.
If I were that capable,
I would already be sitting pretty.
But you were out walking
at the time of the crime.
[Suyeon] Exactly.
The time of my walk and the murder
puts all of us within those confines
- by that logic.
- [Suyeon] That's true.
I have a feeling that Bokgil
is not just a slave.
I grew up with Musoe,
but Bokgil moved in with us
after we were exiled.
And he has many skills.
That's why I think he might be
someone from the outside.
Bokgil. You know…
we agreed to run away together, right?
Yes, we did.
But what I am wondering is,
are you really a slave?
Of course, I am a slave right now.
But I am a dignified slave.
Did someone order you to kill my dad?
It was not to kill--
I'm on your side! I like you.
So right now, you and I
need to be honest with each other.
I do not deal in such matters.
- You said you were out for a walk.
- Yes.
There must have been noises.
Didn't you hear anything?
I did hear a scream,
but I arrived on the scene
after it happened.
- I was a little distance away.
- [sighs] That's your story?
[Igyeong] The important thing is,
I keep wondering
who my daughter really is.
Because why was there a record in her room
- about a baby with a blue mark?
- Right.
[Igyeong] The victim also had
a blue mark on his hand.
If it is a genetic mark,
it ties back to the evidence
the shaman showed us
about the babies being switched.
Yes.
[Igyeong] So, Yun Suyeon…
- [Hwiryeong] She isn't your daughter?
- That's right.
- Not my daughter.
- Not biologically.
And the local female innkeeper testified
that a strange figure came by
looking for Yun Suyeon,
but importantly,
they knew what she looked like.
So the victim could be Yun Suyeon's
- real father?
- Or the person she was switched with.
- Right.
- It could also be her real father.
Mmm…
So I guess she is not your daughter.
I think it is very likely
that my child was switched.
Then what about the switched child?
Who are they?
[Igyeong] I am not sure.
[Suyeon] By the way,
did you have a fling with Musoe?
No, I did not.
I thought she was a man.
That's how little I cared.
But I suspect something
was going on between you
because she wrote you a love note
and even drew a heart on it.
There was nothing between us.
Come on. She has nothing on you.
Do not compare yourself to Musoe.
I dedicated myself to serving your father,
and then you and I became involved,
so I thought it was destiny
and hoped to get away
and live happily together.
Well, what are your thoughts so far?
Is there someone you suspect?
To be honest,
Lord Yun
suspects you the most,
even though you are his daughter.
But I suspect him.
He said he dragged the body.
- Right? In his own words…
- Exactly.
He basically confessed.
It makes no sense
that he dragged the body all that way.
He knows the layout of the house
better than anyone.
The Traveler would not know that well.
He slipped up.
Yes, he confessed by accident.
A dead body isn't easy to drag around.
Yes, you're right.
I think you are right.
Let's live happily together.
Yes. This is your father's problem.
I consider my relationship with you
an honor for a family
that is disregarded like mine.
I think of it as an honor.
So, where should we run away to?
Let us go to Muju.
RIGHT UP MY ALLEY
- Muju Gucheong-dong Valley?
- Yes. Let us go to Muju.
- It is famous for its view.
- Though it's a bit far…
Let's get going, Lady.
Do you want a piggyback?
Sure. Can you manage?
Yes. Get on. Let us go.
[straining, grunting]
[both laugh]
I have a question.
The note we saw earlier said
whoever killed Yun Igyeong
would be appointed to office.
Did you write that,
Grand Prince Hwiryeong?
- Me?
- Yes.
Why would I?
[Musoe] You have the authority…
- Grand Prince Hwiryeong?
-…to appoint someone.
You're in a high enough position.
- He's Grand Prince Hwiryeong?
- Yes.
I'm Grand Prince Hwiryeong.
[both] Your Highness.
Do you understand now?
HE ONLY TOLD YUN SUYEON
AND MUSOE
- How is that possible?
- [Musoe chuckles]
- The truth is--
- I'm supposed to know the grand prince.
[Igyeong] I was exiled for writing
a petition to the King,
and it was the Grand Prince Hwiryeong
who ordered me to do it.
We know each other,
so he can't be Grand Prince Hwiryeong.
CAN'T BE THE SAME PERSON?
Is there a new grand prince?
- Did his role change? Is he retired?
- The truth is,
Grand Prince Hwiryeong is actually…
WHO IS GRAND PRINCE HWIRYEONG?
…he is the one who told me,
"Yun Igyeong is plotting treason,
so he should be
removed from office and exiled."
The grand prince is actually
my younger brother.
WHAT?
[gasps, chuckles]
So, you are the King? Your Majesty?
I am
the ruler of this nation.
What the heck?
WHY DO YOU KEEP CHANGING?
The truth is,
I am the king of this nation.
You've come in person?
That is right.
I have the face of a king.
I didn't mention this earlier,
but I am playing King Sejong in a musical,
and I've played a king on another show.
IS THE TRAVELER REALLY THE KING?
[sighs]
ROUND 3 CARD CLUES
IGYEONG'S DIARY, HUNTER'S WARNING,
INNKEEPER'S STATEMENT
KITCHEN CEILING,
GRAND PRINCE'S LETTER
ROUND 4
Oh, goodness.
I had better take one from Musoe.
YUN SUYEON TAKES
A CARD FROM MUSOE
BOKGIL TAKES A CARD
FROM YUN IGYEONG
MUSOE TAKES ONE FROM YUN SUYEON
THE TRAVELER TAKES ONE
FROM MUSOE
YUN IGYEONG TAKES ONE
FROM YUN SUYEON
[Suyeon] I want this one.
- It is a bit heavy.
- [Bokgil] Let's lift it together.
There's also this.
OBJECT CLUES COLLECTED
This contains a very telling clue.
This belongs to my dad.
Why are you reading my diary?
[Suyeon] "Grand Prince Hwiryeong told me
to submit a petition to the King."
"I also oppose the recent tax reform,
so I put my heart
into writing the petition."
"Grand Prince Hwiryeong is truly
a prince who cares for the people."
The diary is suggesting
that Grand Prince Hwiryeong
is a good person, right?
[Suyeon] Yes.
YUN IGYEONG TRUSTED
THE GRAND PRINCE
Before we discuss this,
Grand Prince Hwiryeong
isn't who he said he was.
Then he's the killer!
- He isn't the killer.
- Actually,
he is our nation's--
[Musoe] You're in real trouble now,
Suyeon.
He is our nation's king.
- I am the King of Joseon.
- [gasps]
- [others laughing]
- Forgive me, Your Majesty!
[♪ dramatic music playing]
KING
RULER OF JOSEON, THE PERSON
WHO SENT YUN IGYEONG INTO EXILE
[contestants] Your Majesty!
[Bokgil] He really is the King.
- All who doubted me, bow your heads!
- Your Majesty.
- His Majesty has a lot of spare time.
- [Suyeon] I'm honestly amazed
that the King wanders around alone.
More like a madman than a king.
HOW INSOLENT
Why did you come here yourself,
Your Majesty?
[King] Despite what it says on here,
the one who sent Yun Igyeong into exile
was actually
the grand prince.
GRAND PRINCE HWIRYEONG PITTED
THE KING AGAINST HIS MINISTERS
A PLOT WAS HATCHED
AMIDST THE CHAOS
BUT THE KING CAUGHT ON
AND WENT INTO HIDING
HE TRACKED DOWN YUN IGYEONG IN EXILE
TO FIND OUT THE TRUTH FROM HIM
So I was tricked
by Grand Prince Hwiryeong?
- You were mistaken.
- I trusted him.
ALLEGIANCE
POLITICAL SCAPEGOAT
- [Suyeon] Musoe.
- I found another knife, goodness.
Why are there so many knives?
[Bokgil] It was under a laundry stone.
Then it must be Musoe's.
- It is my kitchen knife…
- [Bokgil] Hey!
…but because I am so dainty,
I cut my hand…
- [Bokgil] It's your blood?
- Yes.
- Not the murder weapon?
- At the time,
- I had nowhere to wipe it.
- But there's blood here too.
Listen, everyone.
There was a note
in Musoe's recipe book that said,
"Am I…
my master's child?"
Hmm?
Musoe?
- Master? Yun Igyeong?
- Musoe?
From Musoe's recipe book.
[Suyeon] Ah…
- [Suyeon] But--
- Oh!
They were switched!
The switched kids.
So my daughter was…
My real daughter is Musoe.
Yun Suyeon was from a different family
and the victim is her actual father.
But they were switched as kids,
- so he came to find his real daughter.
- [Musoe] He sought her out.
Musoe wasn't just mistaken?
I overheard someone say
that I am Lord Yun's real daughter.
MUSOE HEARD TALK IN THE MARKET
ABOUT YUN SUYEON'S REAL DAD
MUSOE WAS BORN RICH
BUT GREW UP POOR
HER LIFE WAS STOLEN FROM HER,
SO SHE DECIDED TO TAKE REVENGE
FATHER-DAUGHTER
YUN IGYEONG, YUN SUYEON
YUN IGYEONG, MUSOE
They traded lives.
- So she's not a lady, just a slave?
- Yes.
- You two are a good match.
- You're a nobody.
- Birds of a feather.
- Lady, my foot.
- We're a match made in heaven.
- [laughing]
No!
IN DENIAL
You heard it. You two were switched.
- You and Musoe.
- No, I wasn't.
You don't have the facial features
of a noble lady.
OH, MAN
THE SLAVE COUPLE
OF EQUAL SOCIAL STATUS
[Igyeong] If the victim
was revealed to be her father,
who had the most to lose?
She did. Yun Suyeon.
She just wrinkled her nose.
That's a tell when you're guilty.
I have rhinitis…
- Your Majesty.
- [Igyeong] And the victim knew
Yun Suyeon was his daughter,
so she could approach him
without him suspecting her.
When he had his guard down,
she took the silver dagger and…
DID SUYEON STAB HER REAL FATHER?
That's my guess.
But we heard the audio earlier,
a silver dagger could never
make that kind of sound.
The first blade sound was--
The first sound was me.
ME?
In the dark of the night
I heard a noise, so I went out
and something whipped past me,
so I swung my sword as a reflex.
It didn't feel like I struck anyone.
Why did you do such a scary thing?
In the dead of night.
- What a weird king.
- Right?
This is why our nation is in ruin!
It could have been an assassin
sent by Grand Prince Hwiryeong
to take my life.
- So that's why--
- Oh, you thought it was an assassin?
DID HE FEAR ASSASSINATION
EVERY NIGHT?
I have a question for Musoe.
There is a trail of blood
coming out from the kitchen.
So I want to know why
Musoe left the kitchen bleeding
and the trail overlaps here.
I told you I knew you planned
to run away in the night,
so I was out and about at that time.
The truth is that I was jealous of you
since I'm Lord Yun's real daughter,
and now you even stole Bokgil away.
- So I wanted to kill you.
- [Bokgil] Huh?
[Musoe] I even held
the kitchen knife to do it.
- But why is it bloody?
- Why is there blood?
- I never got stabbed.
- [Musoe] But then,
I went to the kitchen to get the knife,
but someone was in there.
I wasn't sure who it was,
but I also felt I was in danger,
so I swung the knife.
So the first blade sound was me.
The one not followed by screams.
What?
[Musoe] And then,
as I was running away, I shook them off,
banged my head, and briefly blacked out
for about 30 minutes.
So there are two people who swung a blade?
WERE THOSE TWO PEOPLE
MUSOE AND THE TRAVELER?
Did you not see their face in the dark?
No, I could not see their face.
It was too dark.
I am not even sure if I struck them.
You said you did the same thing,
Your Majesty.
You swung your sword.
Yes, I swung it.
Based on the time and the route,
I swung my knife first.
THE SECOND SWINGER
IS THE KILLER?
So I find you very suspicious,
Your Majesty.
Well, that narrows it down.
Your daughter, Suyeon,
was actually switched as a child.
All the evidence is
a silver dagger,
a sword,
and a kitchen knife.
Which of those three
had the biggest motive?
I have already made my mind up.
It is Suyeon.
MEANWHILE IN THE EVIDENCE ZONE
SUYEON OPENS A CHEST
Number five, please.
- What's that?
- There's no evidence.
- There's something dangling.
- It's a key!
Am I the only one who can use this key?
Yippee!
HIDDEN CLUE
THE KEY FROM THE SCROLL
CAN BE USED TO OPEN A CHEST
THE PLAYER WHO OPENS IT IS
FREE TO SHARE OR HIDE THE CLUE
What is this?
What is it?
The King's garment.
[gasps]
[whispering] He killed the King!
Then he changed into his robes.
That bastard!
I got chills.
The person who calls himself the King
killed the actual King
and put on the King's robes.
THE TRAVELER IS NOT THE KING?
ROUND 4 CARD CLUES
APOTHECARY NOTE,
RECORD OF OFFICIAL SERVICE
BOKGIL'S NOTE, MUSOE'S RECIPE
BOOK, VILLAGER'S STATEMENT
[host] It is the fifth and final round.
ROUND 5 SHARED CLUE
AUTOPSY REPORT
[Igyeong] An autopsy report.
"Judging by the straight spear wound,
the victim was struck while moving
with a single preemptive strike
by someone highly skilled."
"The wound shows the blade never wavered."
An unwavering blade.
[Bokgil] It must be a sword.
- [Suyeon] But--
- This--
Can we use this right now?
The arm…
Here you go. It is number three.
- Three?
- Yes, three.
SCROLL CLUE NO. 3
YUN SUYEON'S PORTRAIT
There's a blade wound on her neck
and a mark on her hand.
A BLADE WOUND
ON YUN SUYEON'S NECK
AND A BLUE MARK
ON THE BACK OF HER HAND
Lord Yun.
- You need to come and see this.
- [Suyeon] I'd better use mine too.
RUSHING OVER
- [Musoe] That is Yun Suyeon's portrait.
- [Bokgil] Oh.
[Musoe] There's a blade wound on her neck
and a mark on her hand.
She must've done it to get out
of leaving with Bokgil.
- She tried to end her own life?
- Yes.
- To avoid getting caught.
- That's the blood on the silver dagger.
The murder victim
is Yun Suyeon's father,
her biological dad.
But she wasn't trying to kill him.
- She tried to off herself.
- She tried to take her own life.
SUYEON ATTEMPTED TO DIE
She would rather die than live as a slave.
That's why she did it.
The revealed portrait
showed a blade wound on her neck.
I thought it was the victim's blood
on the silver dagger,
but it wasn't.
I am sure that it was
her own blood from trying
to take her own life.
I suspected she was the killer at first,
but the evidence shows that
she harmed herself,
so I don't suspect her anymore.
I'll use mine too.
[sighs] My head hurts.
What's this?
SCROLL CLUE NO. 5
ASSASSIN WARNING NOTICE
That assassin is wearing glasses.
- Bokgil?
- [Suyeon] Hmm…
[gasps]
It's him!
- [Musoe] You're right!
- [Suyeon] It's Bokgil!
THE ASSASSIN LOOKS
JUST LIKE BOKGIL
[Bokgil chuckles]
You're suddenly turning on me like this?
But seeing those glasses,
it really does look like you.
[Igyeong] He also has
a thick head of hair like you.
- I think it's him.
- He's an assassin.
- Bokgil's an assassin.
- Suddenly?
[Musoe] Bokgil seems like an assassin
who was acting under orders.
[Bokgil] I'm an impressive guy like that?
Grand Prince Hwiryeong and the King
seem to have been
engaged in a political conflict
that forms the backdrop.
And Lord Yun got caught
in the middle of it.
And I think Bokgil is an assassin
working under Lord Yun.
WHO HIRED BOKGIL AS AN ASSASSIN?
Bokgil is on His Majesty's side
or one of Grand Prince Hwiryeong's men.
Whether he was sent to protect Lord Yun
or hired to kill someone,
I think that's the gist of his role.
It is true
that I am here under the order
of the grand prince.
- [Musoe] Grand Prince Hwiryeong?
- Yes.
Grand Prince Hwiryeong sent you.
WAS HE HIRED TO ACT AS A SLAVE?
Why did you try to run away with Suyeon?
Because I love Lady Suyeon.
- You fell in love on the job?
- [Suyeon, Bokgil] Yes.
But I had nothing to do with the murder.
I was planning to run away.
Why would I do this and foil my own plans?
You said were ordered
by Grand Prince Hwiryeong.
- Yes, well--
- [Musoe] What were his orders?
- To report back his every move.
- Lord Yun?
Yes, on Lord Yun.
Was it positive surveillance
for his protection?
Who are you to interrogate me?
[Bokgil] That's all I have to say.
But keeping watch is
usually a negative thing.
A government office was promised
to the one who killed Lord Yun
and that person is you, right?
GRAND PRINCE HWIRYEONG
CAUGHT ON TO THE KING'S PLANS
BOKGIL WAS ORDERED
TO ASSASSINATE LORD YUN
[Bokgil] I did consider it
by making a deadly poison
but I didn't even think to use a blade.
I've never used a sword before.
I can't even cut an apple.
Bokgil!
AT THE TIME
THEY AGREED TO RUN AWAY
BOKGIL CHOSE AMBITION OVER LOVE
DID YUN SUYEON TRY TO END HERSELF
BECAUSE SHE FELT ABANDONED?
LOST IN THOUGHT
Lord Yun, why are you suddenly
so quiet?
- I kept suspecting Yun Suyeon…
- Right.
…but now I think you are the culprit.
The figure in the clue we just saw
was wearing glasses, after all.
[King] Bokgil wanted to rise up
through society.
[chuckles]
He really loved Yun Suyeon,
so he wanted to run away with her
and leave his past behind.
But if Suyeon's real father
revealed her identity,
it would mess everything up.
So putting aside
his assignment to kill me,
I think he killed
Yun Suyeon's real father.
If it is true that Bokgil is an assassin,
it says the victim was moving,
but the strike was precise.
It's a kind of feat
that a dainty woman like Yun Suyeon
couldn't easily pull off.
I think the assassin killed the victim
with the single strike of a blade,
then wiped the blood off
with the handkerchief we saw earlier.
I thought it was Yun Suyeon but--
- I am not the killer.
- No, you're not.
I think Yun Suyeon
didn't want to go back to being a slave,
so she tried to take her own life
after seeing her real father.
I think it's one of two people.
These two.
- [Musoe] I agree.
- [Suyeon] It was either Bokgil
or the man who claims to be the King.
Here's what I find suspicious.
I don't believe he is the King,
and here's why.
This is
the garment worn
beneath a king's robes.
Are you wearing one right now?
It's under this robe.
And it is marked precisely
as the King's.
The King is dead.
The King has died.
That person sitting there
in the King's robes
cannot be His Majesty.
WHAT IS THE TRAVELER'S IDENTITY?
I'm Grand Prince Hwiryeong.
Grand Prince Hwiryeong?
- I am the King of Joseon.
- [Suyeon gasps]
THE KING OF JOSEON?
OR AN ASSASSIN?
Sorry, but can I say something?
The King isn't dead.
The King is the killer.
He took off his royal robe,
and in just his undergarments,
he killed the victim
and the blood splattered.
That is why the card says "king."
He got splattered from killing the victim?
The King is the killer?
Yes, His Majesty is the killer.
- It's a bit--
- But that doesn't make any sense
because the King can order
anyone to be executed.
Why go to this trouble at night
- to kill someone?
- I came to protect Yun Igyeong.
- He isn't the King.
- People are disposable to him.
[Bokgil] You're really the King?
IS HE REALLY THE KING?
FRUSTRATED
If the King was going to kill someone…
- This is so hard!
-…he'd sentence them to execution.
[King] Explain to me
- what reason I had to kill the victim.
- [Bokgil] Why go out of his way--
- If the King is guilty…
- Why would I do it?
…what would be his motive?
Lord Yun was the King's closest aide,
so maybe the King came to kill him.
Then I would have killed Lord Yun.
- Why kill that other person?
- That's a good question.
- [Musoe] Grand Prince Hwiryeong--
- Or maybe,
it was you
getting revenge.
REVENGE?
Yeah, it could be you!
Why are you acting innocent?
Your life was ruined, after all.
"I was born as the daughter
of a fancy household,
but I grew up as a slave
for 20 or so years because of you."
It is true I was jealous,
but then I would have killed Lady Yun.
Not if you put the blame
- on the person who switched you.
- I held them responsible.
Honestly, I am so confused.
I thought I had everything
figured out more or less,
but the most important question
of why he was killed is still a mystery.
I will base my vote
on the highest probability.
[chuckles]
Make your closing argument first.
This murder case honestly
has nothing to do with me.
I hope you will vote
for someone who is capable
of skillfully handling a blade.
It makes no sense for me to be the killer.
I was just trying to run away with Bokgil.
I am only guilty of loving Bokgil!
It is the same for me.
We are a package deal.
"Package deal."
My only crime is falling in love.
If we had just run away
30 minutes earlier,
we would never have
even known about the murder.
I am…
a virtuous king.
For the sake of my nation…
- He's so suspicious.
-…I really…
I do not even know who the victim is
or why they were killed.
The first blade swing was me,
but as you heard on the audio clip,
no one screamed after the first swing.
We only heard a scream
after the second swing of a blade.
And I urge you to consider
that conclusive piece of evidence.
I know who it is now.
It's all over.
I think it was Bokgil.
I think Bokgil killed someone
based on a misunderstanding,
and my dad dealt with the body.
I think it's close to something like that.
He said he was taking a walk.
He heard the sound of someone dying,
but there's no proof
of what happened after.
Most of all, it's suspicious
that he is an assassin.
It was Musoe.
She swung a blade,
and she felt cheated out of a good life
so she had plenty of motive to kill.
He confessed that he swung a sword
and there was blood on that garment.
If it was his own blood,
the garment would be torn or something.
There was just a bloodstain
around the stomach area.
VOTING COMPLETE
[host] Here are the voting results.
Yun Igyeong and Musoe got one vote each.
The Traveler also got one vote.
Bokgil got two votes.
- I got two votes!
- Bokgil got the most votes.
I'm the culprit?
I DON'T BELIEVE IT
How could this be?
[host] Bokgil, please stand up
and read the ending scenario.
I cannot believe I'm the culprit.
- Are we wrong?
- Darn.
Where is the keyhole?
A BLEARY-EYED ASSASSIN
[Igyeong] It doesn't seem like he is
capable of killing anyone.
[Bokgil] What is this?
THE SCENARIO VARIES DEPENDING
ON WHICH CHARACTER IS ACCUSED
"The case took an odd turn
and everything pointed to one person.
His secret relationship with Yun Suyeon,
his mysterious actions
on the night of the murder,
and the fact that he was
an assassin sent by Grand Prince Hwiryeong
made everyone see him
as the most dangerous suspect,
even though he was not the culprit."
HEAVY SIGH
Why, you all…
It wasn't me!
"The truth never came to light,
and everyone's suspicions
brought a person to ruin.
After he was bound up and taken away,
his fate became unknown.
No one believed that he had
been fully devoted to Lady Yun."
Bokgil's love was sincere.
I'm tearing up.
THEN WHO IS THE REAL CULPRIT?
"That night,
the person who had slain
Yun Suyeon's real father
was the Traveler."
Ah…
CHILLS
It was the Traveler.
THE CULPRIT WAS THE TRAVELER
[Bokgil] "The King,
disguised as the Traveler,
was the owner
of the bloody sword and handkerchief.
He mistook the victim for an assassin
sent by Grand Prince Hwiryeong
and killed Suyeon's real father.
Because Bokgil was unjustly found guilty,
the King departed from the place of exile
while keeping his identity
a secret until the end."
THE TRAVELER LEFT WITHOUT A CARE
You shouldn't overthink this game.
You need to keep it simple.
I kept telling you.
That bloody garment gave him away.
The King isn't dead.
The King is the killer.
He killed the victim
and the blood splattered.
[chuckling] I was so close.
- [Suyeon] Oh, man.
- I told you so!
I didn't think he was the King.
Why would the King
come all this way in person?
- [Musoe] The evidence was clear.
- [Suyeon] It's ridiculous.
Based on the facts…
- But he had no motive.
- Exactly.
My motive actually
wasn't to kill that person.
It's just that my life has been
at threat since I was a child.
So you had no idea who he was--
You killed him by accident.
What the heck?
We really overcomplicated it.
[Igyeong] I think this is a key clue.
"He was always on guard
and awoke at the smallest sound."
We might have suspected him
if we had seen this clue,
but no one picked this card.
Despite his motive,
everything else fit perfectly.
They're a bunch of idiots.
You can't just accuse an innocent person.
I'm sorry.
[Bokgil] I didn't go
anywhere near the crime scene.
- I was just exercising.
- "Exercising."
Somehow, I got the most votes.
THE FULL STORY
[person] Suyeon.
01:20, SUYEON'S
REAL FATHER APPEARS
Suyeon.
01:22, MUSOE SWINGS
THE FIRST BLADE
01:25, BOKGIL RECEIVES ORDERS
TO KILL YUN IGYEONG
Suyeon.
Sir.
01:30, THE TRAVELER SWINGS
THE SECOND BLADE
01:35, YUN IGYEONG HIDES
THE CORPSE
[howls]
[♪ theme song playing]
Translation by Hannah Og Nam